<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transforms Signals and Systems on rezvan</title>
    <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/transforms-signals-and-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transforms Signals and Systems on rezvan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rezvan.xyz/school/transforms-signals-and-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Summary</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_summary/</guid>
      <description>Signals A signal is a set of information or data. Any physical quantity that varies over time, space or any other variable or variables.&#xA;Even, Odd &amp;amp; Periodic An even function is symmetrical about the vertical axis. Mathematically this means: $$ f(t) = f(-t) \\ f[k] = f[-k] $$&#xA;An odd function is anti-symmetrical about the vertical axis. Mathematically this means: $$ f(t) = -f(-t) \\ f[k] = -f[-k] $$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 9 - Laplace transform</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the Laplace transform and how we&amp;rsquo;ll use it.&#xA;Before that, let&amp;rsquo;s understand why we&amp;rsquo;ll use it.&#xA;What the Laplace transform will allow us to solve are linear differential equations with constant coefficients.&#xA;From what we&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far, we have no way to synthesize exponentially growing signals.&#xA;Therefore: $$ e^{j\omega t} \rarr e^{st} $$&#xA;Where $s = \sigma + j\omega$.&#xA;Definition The Laplace transformation is a unilateral transform, which just means it is one-sided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 8 - Signal reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_8/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll cover how we can recover a signal from a sampled signal, given that it follows Nyquist-Shannons theorem.&#xA;Signal reconstruction If we want to reconstruct a signal from a sampled version, assuming it follows Nyquist-Shannos theorem.&#xA;We have two options. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the first option.&#xA;Filter Given the spectrum of the signal, we can isolate the replica and perform the inverse Fourier transform on this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 7 - Filters and Nyquist-Shannon sampling theorem</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_7/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the important Nyquist-Shannon sampling theorem. This is a fundamental theorem within digital signal processing.&#xA;However, to understand the theorem, we firstly need to understand filters.&#xA;Transfer function Say we have a system which can be modeled as: $$ y(t) = f(t) * h(t) $$&#xA;The same system, but in the frequency domain is therefore: $$ Y(\omega) = F(\omega)\ H(\omega) $$&#xA;Just as we call, $h(t)$, the system response function, we call $H(\omega)$ for the spectral response of the system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 6 - Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll define and understand Fourier transforms. In the last part we covered the concept of Fourier series.&#xA;Which was a way of describing periodic functions as a linear combination (sum) of simple trigonometric functions. The Fourier transform takes this one step further, it&amp;rsquo;s a way to extend the Fourier series of non-periodic functions.&#xA;Definition Given a function in the time-domain, the equivalent function in the frequency domain is: $$ F(\omega) = \int_{-\infty}^{\infty} f(t) e^{-j\omega t}\ dt $$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 5 - Fourier series</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_5/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll try to understand the concept and power with Fourier series.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s firstly define the what, why and how with Fourier series.&#xA;Definition Fourier series, is an expansion of a perodic function, into a sum of trigonometric functions.&#xA;So the power is really, given a complex perodic function, we can easily represent it as a sum of simple trigonometric functions!&#xA;However, before we mathematically define the Fourier series, let&amp;rsquo;s take a different approach to this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 4 - Differential equation models</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_4/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we will learn about systems that can be modeled with differential equations.&#xA;Definition Some systems whose input, $f(t)$, and output, $y(t)$, are related by linear differential equations, often have the form: $$ \dfrac{d^n y}{dt^n} + a_{n - 1} \dfrac{d^{n - 1}y}{dt^{n - 1}} + \ldots + a_1 \dfrac{dy}{dt} + a_0 y(t) = $$&#xA;$$ b_m + \dfrac{d^m f}{dt^m} + b_{m - 1} + \dfrac{d^{m - 1} f}{dt^{m - 1}} + \ldots + b_1 \dfrac{df}{dt} + b_0 f(t) $$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 3 - Convolution</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 21:03:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we will learn about the convolution operation and how it&amp;rsquo;s used.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s start at how it&amp;rsquo;s used.&#xA;Use case Given this signal, we want to find activity on the graph, besides the notice. A kind of high-pass filter will do the job. A high-pass filter is precisely doing the convolution operation to filter.&#xA;For example the output for this input can be: Definition and properties Let&amp;rsquo;s call our input signal $x(t)$, our system operation for $h(t)$ and our output for $y(t)$.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 2 - System properties &amp; LTI</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 22:03:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081_2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this part we will learn to classify systems and recognize a Linear-Time Invariant System&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s first define what a system is.&#xA;Systems Our definition of a system will be:&#xA;An entity that processes a signal/a set of signals to yield another signal/set of signals.&#xA;The input, also called excitation, goes through the system and the system spits out an output, also called response.&#xA;Interconnection We can have multiple systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforms, signals and systems: Part 1 - Signals</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 16:12:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/school/ssy081/ssy081/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this series we&amp;rsquo;ll cover what we mean with transforms, signals and systems. How they relate and are used in the real world.&#xA;Signals In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll try to understand signals, classify these. Perform different signal operations and lastly understand and use signal models. Let&amp;rsquo;s first define what a signal is&#xA;Definition A signal is a set of information or data. Any physical quantity that varies over time, space or any other variable or variables.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
