<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on rezvan</title>
    <link>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on rezvan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 21:00:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rezvan.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Julia projects</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 21:00:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/julia/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently felt the urge to make some math-related projects and visualization projects. So I picked up Julia and have so far learned the basics of the language - it&amp;rsquo;s a quite simple and dynamic language which I appreciate, especially after my most recent projects have been in C/C++ and Rust - it&amp;rsquo;s a great refresh in programming. So far I&amp;rsquo;ve made quite small projects with a lot of built-in libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim-like editor</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 21:04:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/editor/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to learn Rust for a long time - I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled and manged to learn the basic syntax a while ago. However you haven&amp;rsquo;t truely learnt a language until you made a project and the code would be considerd &amp;lsquo;idomatic&amp;rsquo; - or atleast in my opinion. So I decided to make a Vim-like text editor. I took alot of inspiration from this post from medium, so all credits to Kofi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My personal bucket list</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/bucketlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 17:21:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/bucketlist/</guid>
      <description>One day each and one of us will die - this is a universal truth. I am writing this to keep my self accountable and remind my future self to recongize where I was and where I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to.
 Build/own my own place Make a diffrence in the world (well, hard to define) Fall in love Be successful working for myself (finical security) Create something meaningful (film, book, podcast etc) Live in another country Trace my ancestry Read 100 200 books Mentor someone Help someone else achieving their dreams Get a PhD Watch over 200 movies  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial post</title>
      <link>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/initialpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 17:18:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rezvan.xyz/posts/initialpost/</guid>
      <description>This is just a initial post - I&amp;rsquo;ll mainly write about things I find fascinating/interesting on this site :).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
